嗯？稳定得不可思议
Hmm? Surprisingly stable.
嘿 救护车 那是人造能量吗？
Hey Ratchet, is that Synthetic Energon?
嗯 是的
Well, yes.
实际上我正准备测试这些样本
In fact I'm preparing to test the sample.
看来你戴了护目镜
I see that you come equipped with protective goggles.
我可以看了？
I can watch?
哈哈 只需要往测试引擎中注入一些
Haha, We just add some to the test engine.
起作用了！小蜂！
It works! Bee!
等一下 等一下
Dah, dah dah?
在我们考虑将它用来制造燃料
This iteration of the formula requires further trial
弹药 或是急救品之前
before we could even think about using it for fuel
这个配方样本需要进一步的实验
ammunition or first aid
很不幸 因为我们的能量储备一向不足
which is rather unfortunate since our own reserves are in all time low.
敌众我寡 我们的战士为了对付霸天虎而疲于奔命 迅速地消耗着能量储备
Our severely outnumbered warriors have been rapidly burdening through our stockpile of late
造成了霸天虎始终在较量中占据上风
as the Decepticon army continues to run us and ground us down.
天然能量在你们的星球上十分稀缺
Natural Energon is in such short supply on your planet
而且看起来威震天的脏手已经遍布地球
and Megatron seems to have his oily claws buried deep in all the earth deposits.
但是 如果我们能成功制造出人造能量
But, if we can successfully produce a synthetic form
就能解决所有的能源需求问题
we can manufacture all the energy we'll ever need.
有移动的能量矿石信号
Raw Energon on the move.
又来了
Again.
最近的动向表明 他们又重操旧业了
Their recent activity suggests a familiar pattern.
霸天虎们急于探测出新的能量矿
The Decepticons are desperately scouting for new deposits to mine.
汽车人…
Autobots...
擎天柱 如果你们这次回来的时候有人受伤的话 那个
Optimus, if one of you comes back wounded this time, well...
我们能量储备已经几乎耗尽了
our Energon reserves are nearly depleted.
我懂了
Understood.
启动环陆桥
Activate the Ground Bridge.
汽车人 出发
Autobots, roll out.
有时候我真希望自己能派上用场
Sometimes, I wish I could do more.
救护车 醒一醒！
Ratchet, wake up!
呃？
Ugh?
你人不大 嗓门倒是不小啊？
How is it that such small beings can be so loud.
你受伤了吗？你摔倒了
Are you hurt? You fell.
我很好 我…
I'm fine. I'm...
…好得不得了
more than fine.
哈 能量效率提升了三成？
Hah, energy efficiency is of thirty percent?
马达功能处于最佳状态？
Motor functions optimal?
其他人那儿有什么消息吗？
Any word from the others?
击倒 我们就不能直接传送走人吗？
Knock Out, can't we just Bridge out of here?
这个方块背起来很重
This cube is putting some serious drag on me.
我们给汽车人制造的麻烦越多
The more we give the Autobots a work out
他们消耗的能量就越多
the more fuel they burn.
然后我们就能赢得这场能量竞赛
And we win the Energon race.
何况 空中支援来了
Besides, here comes air support.
阿尔茜 后撤 他们人太多了！
Arcee, fall back, you are out-numbered!
我们向来都是以寡敌众
We are always out-numbered.
我们需要那个能量！
We need that Energon!
救护车 锁定阿尔茜的坐标
Ratchet, lock on to Arcee's coordinates
准备紧急传送
and prepare an emergency Ground Bridge.
我锁定了
I'm locked up.
阿尔茜 减速 准备返回基地
Arcee, decelerate and prepare to return to base.
省省吧 救护车 我和对方靠得太近了
Save it, Ratchet, I'm too close.
别做傻事！
Don't be a fool!
她受伤了
She's hurt.
操纵环陆桥
Man the Ground Bridge.
呼呀！！
HOOAAH!
救护车？
Ratchet?
看来汽车人来了个开外挂的
Looks like the Autobots brought in a ringer.
那我们就让他现形吧
Well then I'll ring his bell.
你得等下次了
You'll have to wait.
呼呀！
HOOAAH!
发生了什么？
What happened?
我只看到辉煌的战果
I only saw the glory aftermath
但听起来医生上演了一出单骑破敌的好戏
but I hear the doc was on one Bot ragging machine.
哇！
Whoa...
噢 嘿 小家伙
Oh, hey, little fella.
好吧 你的秘密是什么？
Alright, what's you secret.
没什么秘密
No secret
只是一种我喜欢称它为“合能”的东西
just a thing something I like to call Synthen.
按照隔板记录下来的那些数据合成出来的？
From the data Bulkhead transcribed?
我以为方程式是…
I thought the formula was...
…不完整的？呵呵 不再是了
Incomplete? Hehe, not anymore.
救护车作为猛男要远胜我的聪明才智？
So Ratchet makes a better tough guy than I do a smart guy?
救护车 我质疑你用自己做试验是否明智
Ratchet, I question the wisdom of using yourself as a test subject.
擎天柱 你没看到救护车当时的表现
Optimus, you didn't see Ratchet out there.
简直是大暴发啊
He was an overdrive.
我们都应该试试这个
We should all try this stuff.
或者让救护车多喝点 然后我们就能放个假了
Or give Ratchet more so we can take a vacation.
我承认初期的效果颇为令人期待
I agree that the initial results seem promising
但我建议在机器上做进一步的测试
but I recommend that further testing be confined to machines
而不是在汽车人身上
not Autobots.
虽然现在是敌众我寡 老朋友
Out-numbered, though, we may be, old friend.
但比起战场上的战士
We need a warrior in the laboratory right now
我们现在更需要的是实验室里的战士
more than we need another in the field.
然后 他直接朝我扑过来 于是我
And then, he came right at me, and I...
嗯… 来 小隔 过来打我
well, come on, Bulk, come at me.
我可不想伤到你 老救
I don't want to hurt you, Ratch.
我说 打我！
I said, come at me!
呼呀！
HOOAAH!
那是怎么回事？
What was that?
你有竞争对手了 小隔
You have competition, Bulk.
我比之前要强壮一些
I'm a bit stronger than I used to be.
速度也快了一点 嘿嘿嘿
Also a bit fast, hehaha...
要跟我较量下吗 肌肉车？
Say you could take me, muscle car?
胆小鬼 感觉怎么样？
Wimp. How’s it hummin?
他是不是有些…
Did he just?
更强 更快 更流氓了
Stronger, faster, studlier.
我要始终保持最佳状态
I need to be at the top of my game.
这关乎我们的生死存亡
Our survival depends upon it.
看起来虎子们又找到了一个矿脉
Looks like the Cons hit another vein.
汽车人 出发
Autobots, roll out.
嘿 嘿 我们不应该等等我们的秘密武器吗？
Heyhey, shouldn't we wait for our secret weapon?
这次任务不需要医疗专家
This mission is unlikely to require medical expertise.
但万一你需要额外的火力支援呢？
But you'll never know if you may require additional fire power.
大黄蜂可以操作环陆桥
Bumblebee can handle Ground Bridge duty.
是时候去痛打一顿那些霸天虎了
Time to put some hurt on those Decepticons.
信号很微弱
The signal is weak.
他们就算找到一个矿脉
They may have hit a vein
也找不到多少能量
but they won't find much of Energon pulse
起码这里没戏
not here.
威震天像我们一样急于找到能量
I take some comfort in the fact that Megatron seems as
这个事实倒令人宽慰
desperate to find the stuff as we are.
你们两个在任务中总是这么废话连篇吗？
Do you two always talk this mush during these missions?
汽车人！
Autobots!
没事了
It's alright.
我是一辆救护车
I'm an emergency vehicle.
干吗这么急？
Why the big rush?
我只是想离汽车人臭虫远点
Just trying to get as far as I can from the Autobot stink.
你的老大知道你有一张臭嘴吗？
Does your boss know you have a potty mouth?
也许我该拜访他一下 顺便告诉他
Maybe I should pay him a visit and tell him.
你该进熔毁炉 死轮子
Get melted, wheel-grinder.
熔毁？好提议
Melted? Now there is the concept.
我不会再问第二遍
I won't ask you a second time--
威震天在哪儿？
where is Megatron?
不 不…不！！
No, no--Nooooo!!
我知道的就这些了 真的！
That's all I know, really!
敬酒不吃吃罚酒
Now was that so difficult?
救护车 你在干什么？
Ratchet, what are you doing?
问口供
Get results.
也破坏了原则
And breaking protocol.
那是个霸天虎仆从 劳工等级
That was a Decepticon minor, servant class.
不是战士级别的
Not warrior class.
哦 让我猜你要说什么：我只是个医疗兵
Oh, let me guess: I'm just the medic.
除非万不得已 汽车人从不伤害他人
Autobots do not inflict harm unless all other options have been exhausted.
这就是我们和霸天虎之间的不同之处
It is what separates us from the Decepticons.
哈！现在是讲大道理的时候吗 擎天柱？
Ha! Is this really the time for another lecture, Optimuse?
碰巧发现威震天所在位置的人不是你 对吧？
You didn't just happen to discover Megatron's current location, did you?
而我做到了
Well, I did.
你知道哪里能找到大量的能量矿藏吗？
And you happen to know where there is a stockpile of raw Energon right for the taking?
我知道！
I do!
行了 救护车 冷静点
Come on, Ratchet. Calm it down.
冷静这东西毫无是处！
Calm is the last thing we need!
是冷静让我们失去了塞博特恩！
Calm is what lost us Cybertron!
虎子们有战舰 军队
The Cons have a warship, an army
频繁的能量探测活动
all this Energon scouting.
你不认为威震天在酝酿什么大动作吗？
You think Megatron isn't gearing up for something big?
我们浪费了大量资源
We are squandering our resources
却只能捡他们的残渣剩饭
chasing after his crumbs.
我们本应该去揍他们
When we really should be hitting him hard
现在就去揍他们
and hitting him now...
狠狠地戳到他们的痛处
precisely where it hurts!
直接攻击霸天虎只会招来报复行为…
A direct assault on the Decepticons would only provoke retaliation...
并且导致无法估算的损失
and lead to incalculable losses.
我不会让无辜的人类也卷入危险
I will not endanger innocent human lifes.
但你却不介意将我们卷入危险！
Yet you seem to have no problem endangering ours!
问问飞过山吧！
Just ask Cliffjumper!
噢 我忘记了！
Oh, I forgot!
他今天已经不可能出现在这里了！
He couldn't be here today!
够了！
That's it!
你知道你的问题吗 擎天柱？
You know your problem, Optimus?
你是个如此高大 如此强壮的汽车人
For such a big, strong Bot...
却如此…优柔寡断
you're soft.
你没有抓住机会把威震天砸成废铁！
You didn't pound Megatron into scrap when you had the chance!
错失了那么多良机！
Many chances, in fact!
恐怕人造能量影响了你的判断力 老朋友
I'm afraid that the Synthetic Energon has impaired you judgement, old friend.
我命令你不得离开基地 直至接到新命令
I am confining you to base until further notice.
大黄蜂 把我们传送回去
Bumblebee, bridge us back.
好吧…
Fine...
呼！呀！
Ummmm! Yahhhh!
无法定位救护车的坐标
Can't get a fix on Ratchet's coordinates.
那自负的人造能量一定搅乱了他的信号
That bogus Energon must be scrambling his signal.
继续尝试
Keep trying.
我们必须找到救护车
We've got to find Rathcet
在他找到威震天之前
before he finds Megatron.
是 她是有点跋扈 多出来的手臂也很奇怪
Yeah, she's kinda domineering and the extra arms are weird
但是…我发现自己对她还蛮来电的
but... I find myself intrigued by her.
我还在想你什么时候会送上门来
I was wondering when you might show.
你还配叫科学家？
You call yourself a scientist?
你现在早该找到一处新的能量矿藏了！
You were supported to have located a fresh Energon source by now.
我道歉 威震天陛下
Apologies, Lord Megatron.
一个新汽车人袭击了我们 我们有些分心
We got little distracted by the new Autobot who attacked us.
真的？
Really?
那个新汽车人是谁？
And what new Autobot would that be?
呼呀！
HOOAAH!
呃 那么…
Well, the...
这就是你所谓的新对手？
That is your fiercesome new adversary?
哈哈哈哈哈 他是擎天柱的医疗兵
Hahahaha! He is Optimus Prime's mech.
噢 不 威震天
Oh, no, Megatron.
我是你的验尸官
I am your doctor of doom.
呼呀！
HOOAAH!
那好吧
Alright then.
为了塞博特恩！
For Cybertron!
啊啊 啊啊！
Ahhh, Ahhhhh!
救护车的确比我印象中的要生龙活虎一些
Ratchet is rather more spirited than I recollect.
也许是化学作用？
Chemical enhancement, perhaps?
给你个实验室样本 医生
There is your laboratory sample, doctor.
查明原因
Find out...
如果一种化学药剂可以把擎天柱的医官变成这样 呵呵
If a chemical can do this for Optimus Prime's lab doc, hehe
想想它对我们的军队所产生的影响吧
imagine what it could do for our troops.
噢 擎天柱 我可真傻
Oh, Optimus, I've been a fool.
擎天柱 有救护车的信号
Optimus, Ratchet's signal.
它重新出现了
It's back online.
大黄蜂
Bumblebee.
汽车人 出发
Autobots, roll out.
大家同为医官 我得说
Doctor, to doctor, I must say
感谢你对霸天虎作出的贡献
you contribution to the Decepticon cause is very much appreciated.
我一定会在你死后为你歌功颂德的
I'll be sure to boast of your accomplishment when you are gone.
在我倒数之后会发生什么呢？三 二…
Which will happen in three, two...
该死
Scrap.
哈哈哈哈 你想干什么？
Hahahahah... what are you going to do?
喝了它？
Drink it?
不 我要毁了它
No. I'm going to destroy it.
你这蠢货！
You idiot!
威震天会要了我的脑袋！
Megatron will have my head!
放轻松 老朋友
Easy, old friend.
你失去了很多能量…
You lost a lot of Energon--
喜忧参半
good and bad.
我…我没想过要伤害任何人
I... I didn't intended to hurt anyone.
我只是…
I just... wanted so... badly to...
太想帮忙了
Help us.
我们知道
We know.
但你差点造成了无可挽回的损失…
But you nearly caused the loss of something irreplaceable--
我们的医官
our medic
还有一个值得信赖的朋友
and a most trusted friend.
你的确带我们找到了急需的能量供给
You did lead us to a much needed Energon supply.
为此
And, for that
大家都应该感谢你
we should all be thankful.
很显然 在再次测试之前 人造能量的配方需要进一步改进――
The Synthetic Energon formula clearly needs refining before it can be tested again-
然后通过机器测试 而不是汽车人
on machines, not Autobots.
好在你当场销毁了残余的样本
Let us take comfort in the fact that you
对此 我们值得庆幸
are able to dispose of the quantity that remained.